ANISH JOSHI

anish.joshi06@gmail.com 917.679.5991 LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Experienced in object-oriented programming and broad range of programming languages, particularly Java, JavaScript, C, C++, and Python. In-depth understanding of containerization technologies such as Docker, and cloud computing platforms such as Amazon Web Services and Google Cloud Platform.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Frameworks: Spring Boot, React.js, Node.js, Express.js, AngularJS, Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS3, PHP, jQuery, Android
- Programming Languages: Java, JavaScript, C, C++, SQL, Golang, TypeScript, ES6, Python, C#, GraphQL
- Databases: MySQL, Oracle, MSSQL, MongoDB, Redis
- **Technologies**: Git, ClickUp, Jira, SVN, Docker, AWS, GCP, Nginx, Tomcat, OAuth, J2EE, Linux, Apache Solr, Apache JMeter, Kanban, Junit, Mockito, Maven, Swagger, Kafka, ETL, NoSQL databases, Hibernate, Kubernetes, Postman

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer II, Zulily LLC, Seattle, WA

Feb 2023 - Mar 2023

Built statements for dropship pay orders resulting in increased efficiency for vendor reconciliation.

Software Engineering Intern, Life Tree Services LLC, Buffalo, NY

Jun 2022 - Aug 2022

- Engineered new interface for better management of tree pruning services, yielding to 55% increase in business.
- Improved sales by 28% by implementing dashboard to manage invoices, job status, map-view for job locations, and automatic follow-up emails for local business using Google APIs and SendGrid APIs.
- Optimized job image access for staff by integrating Dropbox APIs, saving staff 30 minutes per day.
- Utilized Intuit's QuickBooks for accounting, revolutionizing accounting practices and producing real-time financial insights, streamlining financial operations, and reduced manual errors.

Senior Software Engineer, Assurekit Technologies & Services, Mumbai, India

Jan 2021 - Aug 2021

- Spearheaded new paradigm for the InsurTech industry to improve customer convenience using SDLC process and agile methodologies while taking charge of daily scrums.
- Mentored team of 5 to foster no-code structure for assurekit.com with ability to function as ERP system with ability to create forms and workflow.
- Pioneered business model, enabling businesses to collaborate with insurers increasing sales by 83%.
- Mapped statistical analysis and graphs of insurance policies, achieving a potent visualization of business.

Software Engineer, Business Solution Group ITSoft PVT. LTD, Mumbai, India

Mar 2016 – Dec 2020

- Modeled entire Core Banking Solution (CBS) platform and architected all related microservices using object-oriented programming (OOP), leading to a partnership with 40+ banks across pan India.
- Devised real-time fraud and risk monitoring system with help of Kafka, reducing potential for cyber-fraud by 90%.
- Developed client-critical modules and created RESTFul APIs comprising of accounting, CRM, remittance, account opening and maintenance, and customer support module with real-time SMS and email services, leading to 40% boost in client's business.
- Revamped core banking module by delivering 50+ functionalities within specified timeline with 0 lapses.
- Programmed Android application for money transfer, boosting transaction time by 85%.
- Incorporated National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI) APIs within CBS for transactions giving rise to 80% success rate.
- Facilitated cross-team collaboration, providing APIs for transactions for loans and other services.
- Implemented caching enhancing transactional speed by 12%.

EDUCATION

Master of Science (MS), Computer Science & Information Science University at Buffalo, The State University of New York

Aug 2021 - Feb 2023

Bachelor of Engineering (BEng), Computer Engineering SIES Graduate School of Technology, University of Mumbai, India

Jul 2011 - Jul 2015